<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Kevin Jalbert</title>
  <link href="https://kevinjalbert.com"/>
  <updated>2020-08-29T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
  </author>
  <id>https://kevinjalbert.com</id>
  <entry>
    <title>My Dam Broke - Revisiting Content Consumption</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/my-dam-broke-revisiting-content-consumption/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/my-dam-broke-revisiting-content-consumption/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-08-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">In this post I revisit the topic of content consumption, adding new criteria to my selection process. I also discuss using a new tool (spoiler...it's Notion) to hold the content.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve previously talked about &lt;a href="/consuming-content-and-managing-the-flood"&gt;managing your content consumption&lt;/a&gt; using metaphors such as a dam, the flow of water, a reservoir, and a spillway. I highly recommend reading through if you are looking for some techniques to tame information overload. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read the above article, the main point is to focus on high-quality sources and don&amp;rsquo;t consume everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert! Even though I wrote the above article, I have to revisit the topic as my metaphorical dam is broken. I&amp;rsquo;m finding myself facing the flood with 300+ articles in the reservoir. In this article, I will revisit content consumption management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;System Check&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a look at my content consumption from a system&amp;rsquo;s perspective. There are four factors at play that determine the backlog of content to consume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pace at which I can consume content from my reservoir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The flow of content from sources making it to my dam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The effectiveness of my dam (i.e., the filter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The effective removal of content that is no longer valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improving the pace at which I can consume content is tricky as it depends a lot on the amount of free time I can devote to it. I decided to focus on the other three factors instead as a way to distil the content down to the most valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reducing the Flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flow of content from sources making it to my dam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;flow of water&lt;/em&gt; was the analogy I used in my dam metaphor for the rate of content coming in. This is tunable and can be controlled. I had advocated highly for the use of newsletters as they are narrow in focus and are filtered for good calibre pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to keep tabs on where the good pieces of content are coming from. The importance and value of consumed content will change over time based on projects and interests. This means that I can remove specific content sources if they are underdelivering in value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I have done organically (i.e., &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll unsubscribe from this newsletter as I don&amp;rsquo;t care about YYYY much anymore&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;), but I want to put more of an objective system in place. To do this, I want to track the volume and perceived value gain from my content sources. I&amp;rsquo;ll then routinely be able to revisit and see what is feeding into my content consumption pipeline and what is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Effectiveness of Dam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of my dam (i.e., the filter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal of consuming content is to extract information and turn that into knowledge, ultimately being able to use that to produce results. With that in mind, the following are three guiding principles I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to use before committing to consuming a piece of content:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the information valuable in the long-term?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritizing long-term knowledge will lead to &lt;a href="https://fs.blog/2019/02/compounding-knowledge/"&gt;compounding knowledge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the information relevant to immediate projects?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term knowledge is needed for the current situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the information uniquely valuable?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are diminishing returns from consuming more content on the same topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I want to maximize the effectiveness and efficiency of knowledge extraction. The first two principles I&amp;rsquo;m carrying over from the previous system of content consumption. The third principle is new and should help improve the effectiveness of my dam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially I want the content to make it through the dam filter if &lt;code&gt;(content is long-term || content is relevant) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; content is unique&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either of the first two principles must be true for the content to be of any value. It is worth noting that having both being true is the best scenario &amp;ndash; the information is relevant and long-term knowledge. The relevancy principle is important to have as I want to make sure that I&amp;rsquo;m not losing short-term gains on the projects and problems I&amp;rsquo;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Filtering Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of something that would be filtered out is an article on &lt;em&gt;upgrading from Rails 5.x to 6.x&lt;/em&gt;. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider this long-term knowledge as eventually, Rails will progress past these versions. There is no relevance for this article based on my current projects, and thus it should be filtered out. If afterwards I now have a project that would have benefited from this information, not all is lost as I would just &lt;em&gt;seek&lt;/em&gt; it, embracing &lt;em&gt;Just In Time&lt;/em&gt; learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example would be pieces of content around &lt;em&gt;empathy in code reviews&lt;/em&gt;. This is great long-term knowledge, as well as relevant to my work. The problem is, I&amp;rsquo;ve already consumed something like this and have extracted and internalized the knowledge. This fails the third principle of being uniquely valuable, and thus I would filter these out. If at a later date, I&amp;rsquo;m doing a presentation or article on empathy in code reviews, I would employ &lt;em&gt;Just In Time&lt;/em&gt; learning to find all relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Effectiveness of Spillway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective removal of content that is no longer valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right before consuming a piece of content from the reservoir, I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit the three principles. A piece of content may have lost relevancy, or is no longer going to provide unique value. This is a quick way of removing content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With hopefully a smaller number of content sitting in the reservoir, this mechanism will be enough. In the event that the reservoir is overflowing, you can quickly sweep through everything and reevaluate. The key is to be ruthless, as important information will likely find its way back to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Notion: The New System&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve previously used a mixture of applications to store consumable content. The main application I have used for articles is &lt;a href="https://www.instapaper.com"&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;. The new system demands more metadata and so I&amp;rsquo;ve made the switch to entirely use &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/?r=6b8d609eb50943419db4d87c67fa558e"&gt;Notion [Referral]&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to use separate applications for podcasts and books, but they&amp;rsquo;ll likely have &lt;em&gt;entries&lt;/em&gt; within Notion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Reservoir&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is in a single database within Notion, these are the following fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A default text field that holds the name of the piece of content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., article, video, podcast, book, twitter thread, etc&amp;hellip;)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A select field that specifies what medium the content resides in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Origin&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., XXXX Newsletter, XXXX Podcast, friend, etc&amp;hellip;)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A select field that specifies how I discovered the piece of content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A URL field that holds the link to the content, which in some cases might be blank depending on the content&amp;rsquo;s type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Criteria&lt;/strong&gt; (Long-Term, Relevant, and Unique)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A multi-select field that indicates the criterion that holds true for the piece of content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value&lt;/strong&gt; (None, Low, Medium, and High)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A select field that indicates the value gained after consuming the piece of content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Created At&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A timestamp field of when the piece of content was added.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These fields address the three principles within the &lt;em&gt;Criteria&lt;/em&gt; field, as well as metadata on how to reduce the flow of content via the &lt;em&gt;Origin&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Value&lt;/em&gt; fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within desktop usage, I make use of the &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/save-to-notion/ldmmifpegigmeammaeckplhnjbbpccmm"&gt;Save to Notion&lt;/a&gt; extension as I can fill in more of the metadata from the browser. Within mobile usage, saving content takes another step as I have to go into Notion and add the metadata. For the most part, I try to make use of my desktop when adding content to the Notion database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Iterate and Evolve&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep making changes and iterate on my content consumption system, hopefully making it better each time. The goal is still to turn pieces of content into information that I can use as knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing I&amp;rsquo;m planning to tackle is the actual consumption part of the system and having a process for knowledge retention.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Working From Home: Family, I'm Busy Now</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/working-from-home-family-im-busy-now/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/working-from-home-family-im-busy-now/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-07-27T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">In this post, I demonstrate how to communicate work meetings to my family while working from home. I use a combination of software and hardware to accomplish an informative and automated solution that provides information about my availability to my family.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this post (still in COVID-19 times), remote working, at least for the short-term, is quite prominent. If I had to guess, remote work will continue to thrive after the COVID-19 pandemic passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve previously written a multi-part series on how to &lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office/"&gt;Improve your Home Office&lt;/a&gt;, and this current post builds on the topic by providing my solution to meeting interruptions by my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Problem: Family Interruptions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My home office is in the basement. During the day, my wife is caring for our two children (3.5 years and 6 months old). She occasionally needs my help for a few minutes here and there. From a timing perspective, I do take breaks, but they might not 100% lineup with when she is seeking assistance/relief. Ideally, she would be able to reach out to me when I&amp;rsquo;m not busy (or in a meeting) and I can come up from my office for a few minutes to help out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I needed a way to communicate my meeting schedule so that my wife could see when I&amp;rsquo;m not available to help. This is going to be more important as my children get older, as they will more likely want to come into my office while I&amp;rsquo;m working. It is worth mentioning that I have a door to my office that I keep closed during the workday &amp;ndash; it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t communicate my availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Solution: Wall-Mounted Tablet Showing Google Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an old &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/32Pn3Wy"&gt;Fire 7 Tablet from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; that I attached to the wall with two &lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2D4SzEM"&gt;Command Picture Hanging Strips&lt;/a&gt; and powered via a long Micro-B USB cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that the tablet screen is always on and showing Google Calendar&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt; view. My wife has her Google Account signed in and only displaying my shared &lt;em&gt;Work&lt;/em&gt; calendar (it only shows busy times). Changes in events are synchronized automatically and are reflected within a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The position of the tablet is on the main floor near the door to the basement. This spot was picked by my wife, as it is a central location during her day. Being able to view the whole day is important as she can better understand my availability and plan her day as well. She is able to see when meetings start/end, and it also captures those impromptu meetings that are made shortly before they begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you use a different tablet (like an iPad)? Sure thing, I just worked with what I had around the house. This is a perfect way to put an old tablet to good use as the processing specs don&amp;rsquo;t have to be good. One thing to note with the Fire tablets, you have to &lt;a href="https://vidabox.com/blog/2017/02/11/hidden-always-on-setting-for-amazon-fire-tablets/"&gt;enable the &lt;em&gt;Always on&lt;/em&gt; setting&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2020/07/11/install-play-store-amazon-fire-tablet/"&gt;install the Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt; to get Google Calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Future Iteration: Indicating in the Basement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my family is downstairs, there isn&amp;rsquo;t any indication of my availability as my solution is only on the main floor. I&amp;rsquo;d like to replicate the same setup in the basement itself, although I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about simply using a &lt;em&gt;busy light&lt;/em&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The busy light would be on/off to indicate if I&amp;rsquo;m busy. I feel that this solution is better for kids as opposed to the calendar schedule solution, as it clear and binary. I would set up the busy light by using a smart light/plug that can be toggled based on my Google Calendar&amp;rsquo;s event start/end times via &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Improve Your Home Office - Miscellaneous Aspects</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office-the-miscellaneous-aspects/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office-the-miscellaneous-aspects/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-06-28T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">This is the fourth (and final) installment of a multi-part series on improving your home office. In this article, we talk about the miscellaneous aspects of your home office that I have not covered (lighting, organization, climate, and personalizations).</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am writing a multi-part article on the topic of improving your home office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office/"&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; was mostly a public service announcement to be aware of your home office and to evaluate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-physical-space/"&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; explores the physical aspects (e.g., room/space, desk, and chair).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-input-output-devices/"&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; explores the input/output aspects (e.g., monitor, keyboard, mouse/trackpad, audio, and video).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 4 (this one) explores the miscellaneous aspects (e.g., lighting, organization, climate, and personalizations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous parts of this series explored the foundation of your home office, along with the required devices that you need to get work done. We&amp;rsquo;re now at the point where we can consider extra aspects that augment and address new ancillary concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Lighting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural light, while nice to have, is inconsistent in intensity and brightness. Ideally, you should have a decent lighting setup where you don&amp;rsquo;t need to depend on natural lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a video perspective, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to take extra care to make sure you have proper lighting. There are plenty of resources on how to achieve this, but the main takeaway is to have more light sources (e.g., &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three-point_lighting"&gt;3-point lighting&lt;/a&gt;). To create softer light on your face, you might want to explore putting a light diffuser on your main light source (there are many do-it-yourself options out there, see mine in the picture above).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that your eyes are hurting from looking at your monitor, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to add some &lt;a href="https://powerpractical.com/pages/what-is-tv-bias-lighting"&gt;bias lighting&lt;/a&gt;. There is a very affordable solution in the form of &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Luminoodle-USB-Bias-Lighting-Backlight/dp/B076X89GRW"&gt;LED strips you attach behind your monitor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colour and warmth of your lights are also important &amp;ndash; you can go with &lt;em&gt;warmer/yellow&lt;/em&gt; lights for a relaxing feel, or &lt;em&gt;colder/white&lt;/em&gt; lights for a focus feel (read more &lt;a href="https://www.zmescience.com/medicine/mind-and-brain/lighting-and-mind-study/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). A nice addition is to use smart light bulbs that allow you to change the colour as desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-smart-led-light-bulbs/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best smart LED light bulbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-floor-lamps-under-300/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best floor lamps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-led-desk-lamp/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best desk lamps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Climate Control&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking care of your office&amp;rsquo;s environment will result in better productivity. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2019/jul/08/indoor-carbon-dioxide-levels-could-be-a-health-hazard-scientists-warn"&gt;CO2 and impurities in the air could result in lower cognitive performance&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to monitor these levels, investing in an air purifier if there is little air circulation for your office. If budget is a concern, there are affordable fixes (adding real plants) to improve air quality. Regular cleaning of your workspace will help reduce allergens like dust and pollen (if near a window).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Temperature is another factor that can increase/decrease comfort and focus in your workplace. Depending on your space, you might need to invest in a space heater or air conditioning unit. Suffer from cold hands? Check out these interesting solutions &amp;ndash; &lt;a href="https://envavo.com/"&gt;Envavo&lt;/a&gt; desktop heater as well as using sous vide machine (&lt;a href="https://mastery.games/post/warm-coding-hands/"&gt;read more about this unique solution&lt;/a&gt;). Be resourceful, see what works for you and your space and make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in a part of the world where the winter blues hit hard and you are prone to SAD (Seasonal Affective Disorder), you might want to try using a light therapy lamp. These lamps are designed to be bright enough (10,000 lux) to simulate daylight earlier in the day to control a shifting circadian rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-home-air-quality-monitor/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best home air quality monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-air-purifier/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best air purifier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-space-heaters/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best space heaters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-light-therapy-lamp/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best light therapy lamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Organization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your workspace&amp;rsquo;s organization can have an impact on your mental state. Disorganization could result in added friction and chaos. Ideally, everything has a &lt;em&gt;home&lt;/em&gt; and is generally kept in check. How you organize your workspace depends entirely on what you need and how you do your work. A great strategy is to &lt;em&gt;reset&lt;/em&gt; everything at the end of the day so that you can start fresh the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With many electronic devices, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a power supply to keep them charged and running. You will likely need more than 2-4 electrical outlets, which is where a power bar will be important. It is advisable to not cheap out on this - make sure you have a surge protector on your power bar that is capable of supporting the load. There are nice outlet positions and form-factors, but the end goal is to increase the number of available outlets for your usage. USB hubs are also ideal, as they allow for more connection ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, cables and wires will run rampant on and around your desk. You can keep this problem in check with proper cable management. There are plenty of ways to do this and there are plenty of unique product solutions out there. I highly recommend taking a look at &lt;a href="https://bluelounge.com/collections/cable-management"&gt;Bluelounge&lt;/a&gt; for comprehensive solutions, or just picking up &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.ca/gp/product/B001E1Y5O6"&gt;velcro fasteners&lt;/a&gt; for a quick way to keep groups of wires together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wall cabinets and shelving are great for more storage opportunities, as well as giving you a place to sort and organize important documents. A cabinet is a great way to store less reached for items. I recommend expanding the organization and storage space you have only as you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-surge-protector/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best surge protector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-usb-c-hubs-and-docks/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best USB-C hubs and docks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-usb-hubs/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best USB 3.0 hubs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-desktop-organizers/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best desktop organizers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Personalization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding personal touches to your workspace can be rewarding. If you have the desire to showcase some art or collectables go for it, especially if they bring you joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend adding some plants to your home office as there is a &lt;a href="https://www.wework.com/ideas/office-design-space/benefits-of-indoor-plants-in-the-office"&gt;lot of research backing the benifits&lt;/a&gt;. If you want a low maintenance plant, succulents are very easy to care for. If you want no maintenance (albeit lower or no benefits), you can get fake plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have specific needs in your home office that require specific tools. You need to address that and make sure you give space and attention to them. For example, if you process a lot of paper, a document scanner and shredder would be good. If you need to draw or whiteboard in digital space, a tablet would be ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Constant Improvement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home office is a project you can keep chipping away at &amp;ndash; constantly improving it or changing it as your needs change. Working with your space and tools will help you figure what is adding friction or could be improved. Keep an eye on cost as it is easy to run up a large bill when tailoring your office to fit your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wraps up the multi-part series on improving your home office. This is a topic that could be written in incredible depth, and I merely scratched the surface. I hope that throughout this you got some new ideas and will be better equipped to work from home in this current situation as well as whatever the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Improve Your Home Office - Input/Output Devices</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office-the-input-output-devices/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office-the-input-output-devices/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-05-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">This is the third of a multi-part series on improving your home office. In this part, we talk about the input and output aspects of your home office (monitor, mouse/keyboard, audio, and video).</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am writing a multi-part article on the topic of improving your home office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office/"&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; was mostly a public service announcement to be aware of your home office and to evaluate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-physical-space/"&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; explores the physical aspects (e.g., room/space, desk, and chair).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 3 (this one) explores the input/output aspects (e.g., monitor, keyboard, mouse/trackpad, audio, and video).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-miscellaneous-aspects/"&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt; explores the miscellaneous aspects (e.g., lighting, organization, climate, and personalizations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The input and output devices are the interfaces that exist between you and your workspace. You&amp;rsquo;ll want devices that offer sublime interactions that reduce friction and bring great pleasure to your work. This will make working in your space a joy instead of a burden. This is paramount in collaborative tasks as poor devices can hinder the experience for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Display&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using a laptop, the screen size and location of it relative to your keyboard and yourself play a critical role in ergonomics. You can elevate your laptop&amp;rsquo;s screen to an optimal height using a laptop stand for improved ergonomics. If your space permits it, you can extend your display with an extra monitor or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extra monitor are wonderful investments for a dedicated home office &amp;ndash; they provide a larger workspace. When purchasing a monitor, make sure it is tailor to your needs. Monitor arms are a great way to minimize monitor footprints and maximize your physical workspace. If your desk supports these it opens up the flexibility to position your monitor at the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To take your display further, make use of multiple monitors. You can get creative with combinations of monitor arms and the position/orientation of your multiple monitors. You could also consider ultrawide monitors &amp;ndash; single unit monitors that offer similar space advantages as multi-monitors without the added bezel separating the monitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-monitors/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best monitors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-monitor-arms/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best monitor arms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-laptop-stands/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best laptop stands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Audio&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a home office, we&amp;rsquo;ll have to consider both audio input and audio output for effective collaboration. As a default, most people using a laptop will have their built-in speakers and mic on their device. These work in a pinch, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of room for improvement in quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solid upgrade is using a headset as it brings the audio closer to your head. Your voice will sound better as the distance from your mouth to the mic input is closer (even better if you have a headset with a boom arm). This solution will also only broadcast audio out to your ears and not fill your space (preventing feedback and adding privacy). Given the environmental noise in your space, it might be worth looking at the noise-cancelling feature of whatever headset/earbud you decide to go with. A wireless headset is a great option if you value mobility and less clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your personal preference, a good headset can support all your audio listening needs. There are some high-quality headsets out there that provide immersive and great sound quality for music. Alternatively, using external computer speakers that sit on your desk can be an attractive solution for an experience that fills your space with rich and deep sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for that professional podcasting audio sound you should look at an external USB microphone. These offer great input capture and offer much more customization and tweaking if you decide to explore that route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the minimum, you should probably get a headset to conduct meetings. Going for more elaborate setups and devices in this space really depends on your taste and desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-wireless-headset-for-the-office/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best wireless headset for the office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-noise-cancelling-headphones/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best noise cancelling headphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/the-best-usb-microphone/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best USB microphone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-computer-speakers/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best computer speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Webcam&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A visual presence in collaborative meetings is a must-have in any remote working environment. Being to see each other gives meetings more of a &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; feel and allows each side to see facial expressions and body language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most laptops these days have a built-in webcam that is sufficient. There are two caveats with the built-in solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The angle and position of the webcam is tied to your laptop itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The video quality is lacklustre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dedicated high-quality webcam rectifies these two issues. It can be moved to optimal positions and the picture quality is far superior. If you wanted to go the extra mile, you can look at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21244380/webcam-camera-how-to-dslr-mirrorless-capture-card-usb-hdmi"&gt;using a DSLR or mirrorless camera as a webcam&lt;/a&gt;. This is a much more expensive route, but the video quality is the best you can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resource is recommended reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/the-best-webcams/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best webcams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Keyboard&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d argue that the keyboard is the most used device you have. As with most things related to home offices, there is a lot of personal preference when it comes to keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a strong &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MechanicalKeyboards/"&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; for mechanical keyboards that offer near unlimited customization options. To start with, you can vary the size, keycaps, and key switches to fit your style. These customizations create unique typing experiences that can be more enjoyable and ergonomic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a large space for ergonomic keyboards &amp;ndash; defined by their unorthodox physical layout. For example, the &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/accessories/en-ca/products/keyboards/sculpt-ergonomic-desktop/l5v-00002"&gt;Microsoft Sculpt Ergonomic Desktop&lt;/a&gt; has a defined split and curved design. Most ergonomic keyboards fall under the mechanical keyboard umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you value a clean work surface a wireless keyboard is a nice way to minimize wire clutter. It is worth noting that oftentimes the higher-end mechanical keyboards require a wired connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/our-favorite-mechanical-keyboards/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s our favorite mechanical keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/comfortable-ergo-keyboard/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best ergonomic keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/the-best-bluetooth-keyboard/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best bluetooth keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Mouse&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mouse is the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B6rKUf9DWRI"&gt;original pointing input device&lt;/a&gt; and has been a staple for all personal computing since its inception. For most people, the mouse covers all their needs. Like previous suggestions, a wireless device provides a clean solution on a desk. The &lt;a href="https://www.logitech.com/en-ca/product/mx-vertical-ergonomic-mouse"&gt;vertical mouse&lt;/a&gt; is a more ergonomic variant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trackball mouse is an ergonomic departure from a traditional mouse in the sense that you move your cursor by spinning a ball on a fixed mouse. The idea is that you reduce arm motion and you an keep your hand and arm in an ergonomic position. If desk space and/or ergonomics are a concern, this type of mouse might be a good solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are familiar with trackpads &amp;ndash; almost, if not every, laptop comes with one. Using an external trackpad occupies less space than a mouse and is usually wireless. You gain access to gestures based on your operating system, and using them feels fairly intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor ergonomics can lead to &lt;a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/carpal-tunnel-syndrome/symptoms-causes/syc-20355603"&gt;carpal tunnel syndrome&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; if needed, switch up your device to relieve the discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-wireless-mouse/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best wireless mouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-gaming-mouse/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best wired gaming mouse mouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/best-trackballs/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best trackballs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Powerful Subtle Interfaces&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interactions between yourself and a computer are driven entirely through input and output devices. Ergonomics is key, especially for prolonged use. Having a good set of devices allows you to focus more on your work with less hindrance. Pay attention to the purchasing cost of devices as there are diminishing returns with expensive products.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Improve Your Home Office - Physical Space</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office-the-physical-space/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office-the-physical-space/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-04-28T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">This is the second of a multi-part series on improving your home office. In this part, we talk about the physical aspects of your home office (space, desk, and chair).</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am writing a multi-part article on the topic of improving your home office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office/"&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; was mostly a public service announcement to be aware of your home office and to evaluate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part 2 (this one) explores the physical aspects (e.g., room/space, desk, and chair).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-input-output-devices"&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt; explores the input/output aspects (e.g., monitor, keyboard, mouse/trackpad, audio, and video).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-miscellaneous-aspects/"&gt;Part 4&lt;/a&gt; explores the miscellaneous aspects (e.g., lighting, organization, climate, and personalizations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical space is the foundation on which the rest is built. Without a good location for your home office, it can be hard to get &lt;em&gt;deep work&lt;/em&gt; done. The following dissects aspects of the physical space of a home office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Space&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A home office is a place to focus and work, thus it is paramount to keep external distractions at bay. The space that you use for your home office will contribute greatly to how productive you might be. Having your office in a common area (e.g., living room) is pretty much fighting a losing battle if you live with other people (family/friends).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If space allows it, I highly recommend placing your home office in its own dedicated room. If that isn&amp;rsquo;t possible, the next best place would be a shared space with minimal traffic. A dedicated office space creates boundaries. When your space&amp;rsquo;s functionality and location bleed into other areas, it can blur the line between work and home time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When deciding where your home office should be, there are various environmental factors to take into account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being in a basement might limit natural light and the ability to get fresh air, and also prove noisy from the activity above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being near a window (which you want to open occasionally) or other noisy space can be distracting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being near a window can also introduce annoying glare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being aware of air/heat circulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware of the size of your space. Opt for a location where you can have a decent space for working, along with some space to store/place miscellaneous items. Having the extra room gives you some freedom in how to structure your space, and can open some customization opportunities (e.g., fitness equipment, whiteboard, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Desk&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your desk is something that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to skimp on if possible. If you are planning to use the home office long term, I would avoid the following: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I just use my countertop or kitchen table. I just sit on the couch and use my lap&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. If you spend long periods of time working in your home office then ergonomics and a dedicated surface are key. Once you decide on your space, I would try to maximize the surface size of your desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of desk options out there, and it really boils down to what works for you and your space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desk with built-in drawers and/or a hutch for extra storage space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desk that supports clamps for monitor arms (i.e., good thickness/strength and an open back).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desk that has an ergonomic bezel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desk that can support a lot of weight if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desk that is esthetically pleasing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A standing desk (fixed or adjustable) to avoid sitting all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An L-shaped desk for corner offices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a standard desk and are looking to explore the sit/stand or stand options, you could take a look at &lt;em&gt;Standing Desk Converters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources are recommended readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-standing-desk/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best standing desks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-standing-desk-converters/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best standing desk converters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Chair&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are working at a desk then you will likely spend many hours sitting on a chair (unless you have a standing desk). A basic wooden chair works in a pinch, but for the long term, you&amp;rsquo;ll want a chair that offers more adjustability and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like the desk, there are plenty of options available, most of it comes down to personal preference. For that reason, I highly recommend going with a chair that you can sit in before purchasing. The following are some factors to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair with casters to move around easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair that has adjustable or removable features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair that is breathable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair that is comfortable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kneeling_chair"&gt;kneeling chair&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://www.uncagedergonomics.com/blog/what-is-an-active-chair/"&gt;active wobble chair&lt;/a&gt; or yoga ball&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing to consider is a standing desk mat if you decide on the standing desk route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resource is a recommended reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-office-chair/"&gt;Wirecutter&amp;rsquo;s best office chairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Lay the Foundation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take care to pick the right physical space for your home office as it is the foundation upon which everything else is built. The right desk and chair will have to fit within that space comfortably. You can tailor your space to maximize productivity and comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Improve Your Home Office</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/improve-your-home-office/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-03-30T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">Due to COVID-19 (Coronavirus), self-isolation brought on a wave of new people working from home, with varying states of home offices. This is the first of a multi-part series on improving your home office. In this part, we focus on evaluating your current setup.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the time of publishing (March 31, 2020), &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019"&gt;COVID-19 (Coronavirus)&lt;/a&gt; is a global pandemic and affecting much of the world. Most places are practicing social distancing and self-isolation. Some companies have switched to remote work by having their employees work from home during this time. As such, an influx of home office interest (&lt;a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=2020-01-01%202020-03-31&amp;amp;q=home%20office,working%20from%20home"&gt;Google Trends shows a huge spike&lt;/a&gt;) has surfaced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing a multi-part article on the topic of improving your home office. This first one is to serve as a public service announcement given how many people are working from home due to COVID-19, and that they should evaluate and explore options to improve their setup to make work more effective and ergonomic. Subsequent parts will focus on different aspects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-physical-space/"&gt;The physical aspect&lt;/a&gt; (e.g., room/space, desk, and chair)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-input-output-devices/"&gt;The input/output aspects&lt;/a&gt; (e.g., monitor, keyboard, mouse/trackpad, audio, and video)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/improve-your-home-office-the-miscellaneous-aspects/"&gt;The miscellaneous aspects&lt;/a&gt; (e.g., lighting, organization, climate, and personalizations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Evaluate your Home Office&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are fortunate enough to be able to work from home in these times (or you normally work remotely), you should take a few minutes to evaluate your current setup. Within a typical office, there will be fewer opportunities to modify your workspace to best conform to your specific needs. Changing your work setup can result in productivity gains and added comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at your home office. Are you working at the kitchen table, or maybe from the couch? You might laugh, but in those first few days when people were making the switch to working from home, this might have been their reality. Ideally, you&amp;rsquo;d have a dedicated space for your work with a multitude of ergonomic features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating an amazing home office can be a time and money sink as there are numerous items and options to furnish your setup. Fortunately, you can &lt;em&gt;chip&lt;/em&gt; away at the setup and slowly make additions over time as needed. Figure out what is causing discomfort and slight changes or upgrades may remedy the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Return on Investment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll want to think of how much the home office and the individual pieces will be used. There&amp;rsquo;s no point in going overboard with something that you would rarely use, in which case a cheaper or alternative solution might be best. With the COVID-19 situation, this warps the &lt;em&gt;how much am I going to use this afterwards&lt;/em&gt; question, just something to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invest in where you spend your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is advice to avoid wasting resources in improving specific areas of your home office. You can always incrementally improve your office (i.e., improve the weakest, missing, or most used aspects of your space). There will be some items and changes that you can do to your home office that will have huge returns on investment in areas such as comfort, ergonomics, and productivity. Before making changes, be mindful of the return on your investment (i.e., you take a lot of meetings and so you&amp;rsquo;ll gain a lot from a great audio/video setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Wirecutter is Awesome&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many articles circulating around the Internet on the subject of remote work and home offices. I did find that &lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/"&gt;Wirecutter&lt;/a&gt; has several great articles on the subject and they all link to their amazing &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Best xxxx&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; reviews. For some quick wins, I highly recommend skimming the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/lists/how-to-create-a-full-time-work-space-at-home/"&gt;How to Create a Full-Time Work Space at Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/blog/work-from-home-starter-kit/"&gt;The WFH Starter Kit: What Companies Should Provide You With When You Work From Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/blog/productivity-home-office-upgrades/"&gt;4 Small Home Office Upgrades That Can Give a Big Boost to Your Productivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thewirecutter.com/lists/the-essential-ergonomic-gear-for-your-home-office/"&gt;The Essential Ergonomic Gear for Your Home Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Moving from RSS Feeds to Email</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/moving-from-rss-to-email/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/moving-from-rss-to-email/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-02-28T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">Read about how I moved away from RSS Feeds to emails to consume content. I take advantage of newsletters and IFTTT to ensure that everything moved over to email.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve briefly mentioned using RSS to email in &lt;a href="/consuming-content-and-managing-the-flood/"&gt;Consuming Content and Managing the Flood&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I want to further describe this approach and how I&amp;rsquo;ve effectively moved away from RSS Feeds towards emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;RSS Readers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the day, Google Reader was one of the most popular RSS reading services. I ended up using it and thoroughly enjoyed it. I was heavily invested in using RSS feeds and piped all the content I wanted through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, Google Reader was shut down and I made the move to &lt;a href="https://feedly.com"&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;. I was not 100% happy with that service and decided to try a new approach with respect to consuming content from sites with RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;RSS Reader to Email (via Newsletters)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal was to see how I could achieve the same content consumption but without using RSS readers. My idea was to see if I could consolidate the services that I used daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that a lot of the content I was following via RSS had email newsletters. Newsletters worked out well for me, as they contained generally the same information. This also fit in with the whole &lt;em&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/em&gt; movement, as I treated my email inbox as a list of &lt;em&gt;actionable items&lt;/em&gt; that I needed to address. I could work through these emails at my own pace, and if needed I could defer an item by pushing it into &lt;a href="https://www.instapaper.com"&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there were still some RSS feeds that didn&amp;rsquo;t have an email newsletter option. In most cases, these feeds were for different content (e.g., screencasts, comics, music).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;RSS Reader to Email (via IFTTT)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; since it came out. Once again, I reached for this tool to help me with migrating the remaining RSS feeds to email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach is quite simple as we&amp;rsquo;re taking advantage of the &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/feed"&gt;New Feed Item Trigger from the RSS Feed Service&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/email"&gt;Send me an email using the Email Service&lt;/a&gt;. When setting up a new applet, you just have to put in the RSS feed URL and that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ifttt applets" width="1978" height="1038" src="/images/2020-02-29-moving-from-rss-to-email/ifttt-applets.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The applets check and execute within seconds of when a new RSS item arrives. This results in rich-text emails being sent containing the content of the feed item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Email" width="1484" height="814" src="/images/2020-02-29-moving-from-rss-to-email/email.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alternatives to IFTTT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did find other alternatives to IFTTT that would accomplish the same end goal of getting RSS feed items into my email inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://zapier.com/"&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; - you will have to pay if you want more tasks (&amp;gt; 100) and zaps (&amp;gt; 5).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blogtrottr.com/"&gt;Blogtrottr&lt;/a&gt; - has ads incorporated in the emails unless you pay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://feedrabbit.com/"&gt;Feedrabbit&lt;/a&gt; - only allowed 10 subscriptions before you have to pay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I found IFTTT to be a scalable and free solution that fits my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Testing the Use of Rails Caching</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/testing-the-use-of-rails-caching/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/testing-the-use-of-rails-caching/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2020-01-29T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">There is a strong test culture for Rubyist using Rails. Caching can be rewarding in performance, yet can introduce cache complexities. Read about how I approach testing low-level caching.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was doing some performance work within a Rails application where expensive (computationally) data was being generated on each request. It was quick to implement the low-level caching that wrapped the expensive data generation. In this particular case, I wanted to ensure that the caching logic was valid as there were numerous conditions at play. I normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t test caching if the cache key was something trivial (or automatic like using &lt;code&gt;ActiveRecord#cache_key&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation and naming things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Phil Karlton (&lt;a href="https://martinfowler.com/bliki/TwoHardThings.html"&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Peering into the Cache&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Rails application had the &lt;code&gt;cache_store&lt;/code&gt; set to &lt;code&gt;:memory_store&lt;/code&gt; in the test environment. We wanted to make sure that our tests were still going through the same code paths as would happen in production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# config/environments/test.rb:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="no"&gt;Rails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;application&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;configure&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;cache_store&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ss"&gt;:memory_store&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inner data structure of &lt;code&gt;ActiveSupport::Cache::MemoryStore&lt;/code&gt; is not publically accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[1] pry(main)&amp;gt; Rails.cache.write('my-cache-key', 'my-value')
=&amp;gt; true
[2] pry(main)&amp;gt; Rails.cache
=&amp;gt; &amp;lt;#ActiveSupport::Cache::MemoryStore entries=1, size=260, options={}&amp;gt;
[3] pry(main)&amp;gt; ls Rails.cache
ActiveSupport::ToJsonWithActiveSupportEncoder#methods: to_json
ActiveSupport::Dependencies::ZeitwerkIntegration::RequireDependency#methods: require_dependency
ActiveSupport::Cache::Store#methods: delete  exist?  fetch  fetch_multi  logger  logger=  mute  options  read  read_multi  silence  silence!  silence?  write  write_multi
ActiveSupport::Cache::MemoryStore#methods: cleanup  clear  decrement  delete_matched  increment  inspect  prune  pruning?  synchronize
instance variables: @cache_size  @data  @key_access  @max_prune_time  @max_size  @monitor  @options  @pruning
class variables: @@logger
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;raw&lt;/em&gt; data is held in the instance variable &lt;code&gt;@data&lt;/code&gt;. We can &lt;em&gt;reach in&lt;/em&gt; and grab that to perform some inspections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;[4] pry(main)&amp;gt; Rails.cache.instance_variable_get(:@data)
=&amp;gt; {"my-cache-key"=&amp;gt;#&amp;lt;ActiveSupport::Cache::Entry:0x00007f8ade4da858 @created_at=1580064434.3177679, @expires_in=nil, @value="my-value", @version=nil&amp;gt;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The caveat of this approach is clear, as we&amp;rsquo;re reaching into the private space of the Rails cache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Creating the Helper&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make it easier for myself and others to test Rails caching in this project. Creating a test helper is ideal as all the tests can reach for the built utilities when testing code related to caching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll create a new test helper, that can be included in our &lt;code&gt;test/test_helper.rb&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# test/support/rails_cache_helper.rb:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;RailsCacheHelper&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="no"&gt;Rails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;cache&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;clear&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;yield&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="k"&gt;ensure&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="no"&gt;Rails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;cache&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;clear&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;cache_has_value?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;cache_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;any?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;key_for_cached_value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;cache_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;values&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;entry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="kp"&gt;private&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="k"&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;cache_data&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="no"&gt;Rails&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;cache&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;instance_variable_get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;:@data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helper gives us three utilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/code&gt; method, which purges the cache before and after the &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; is executed. It is worth noting that the &lt;code&gt;:memory_store&lt;/code&gt; is only purged at the end of the test suite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;cache_has_value?(value)&lt;/code&gt; method, which returns a &lt;em&gt;boolean&lt;/em&gt; if the cache has the specified &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;key_for_cached_value(value)&lt;/code&gt; method, which returns the &lt;em&gt;key&lt;/em&gt; that can be used to look up the specified &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these new methods, it was much easier to test the caching code. There was no need to do any fancy stubbing and/or using mock objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: there are more features that can be expanded upon in this helper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with the meta-data on cache entries (e.g., &lt;code&gt;expires_in&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom assertions (e.g., &lt;code&gt;assert_cached(value)&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Testing Rails Caching&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I was able to test the caching specifically. I wrapped my tests in &lt;code&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/code&gt; as these tests were specific about using caching. I could have also approached this by making it so the cache is purged before each test (e.g., &lt;code&gt;setup()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;before(:each)&lt;/code&gt;), but I didn&amp;rsquo;t opt for that right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a contrived example, but you could imagine that the &lt;em&gt;cache key&lt;/em&gt; is generated much deeper in the application code. This makes it difficult to &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; the cache key to then inspect and make assertions about the cached data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;RailsCacheHelper&lt;/code&gt; (that we created above), we can make use of &lt;code&gt;#cache_has_value?&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;#key_for_cached_value&lt;/code&gt; to make assertions based on the returned value without needing to know the &lt;em&gt;cache key&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight ruby"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# test/caching_test.rb&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;CachingTest&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;ActiveSupport&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="no"&gt;TestCase&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="nb"&gt;test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'caching works'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# bunch of test setup ...&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Caching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expensive_call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;some_object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data_structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;request_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;assert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cache_has_value?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="nb"&gt;test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'caching is not used if request header specifies caching=false'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# bunch of test setup, and adding caching=false in request_data ...&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Caching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expensive_call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;some_object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data_structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;request_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;assert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cache_has_value?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="nb"&gt;test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'cache varies correctly based on object'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# bunch of test setup ...&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;original_result&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Caching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expensive_call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;some_object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data_structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;request_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;original_key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;key_for_cached_value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;original_result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# setup different_object&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;changed_object_result&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;Caching&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nf"&gt;expensive_call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;different_object&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;data_structure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;request_data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="n"&gt;changed_object_key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;key_for_cached_value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;changed_object_result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

      &lt;span class="n"&gt;rufute_equal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;original_key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;changed_object_key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="nb"&gt;test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'cache varies correctly based on data structure'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# pretty much same as the last test but varying the data structure&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class="nb"&gt;test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'cache varies correctly based on request data'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;with_clean_caching&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# pretty much same as the last test but varying the request_data&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that this approach worked for me, however, there are many different ways to test Rails caching. For example, this &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/9603083/583592"&gt;StackOverflow answer&lt;/a&gt; suggests making an &lt;code&gt;InspectableMemoryStore&lt;/code&gt; which subclasses &lt;code&gt;ActiveSupport::Cache::MemoryStore&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Consolidating Notion Projects into notion-toolbox</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/consolidating-notion-projects-into-notion-toolbox/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/consolidating-notion-projects-into-notion-toolbox/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2019-12-27T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">I made the decision to consolidate all my Notion related projects into a single repository. The goal is to increase cohesion to allow the tools to better interact with each other. Read more about how I did it and why.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a good part of 2019, I focused heavily on my &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/?r=6b8d609eb50943419db4d87c67fa558e"&gt;Notion[Referral]&lt;/a&gt; setup. I personally feel that this was time well invested, akin to a craftsman refining his tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created a &lt;a href="https://kevinjalbert.com/my-weekly-notion-setup/"&gt;specific weekly/daily template&lt;/a&gt; to satisfy some of my needs and give structure to Notion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created an integration with &lt;a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/"&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/alfred-notion"&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfred-notion&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://kevinjalbert.com/integrating-notion-with-alfred/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created a server web application called &lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/notion-heroku"&gt;&lt;code&gt;notion-heroku&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that interacts with &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt; and Google Assistant (&lt;a href="https://kevinjalbert.com/integrating-notion-with-google-assistant/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I created a shared repository called &lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/notion-scripts"&gt;&lt;code&gt;notion-scripts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to further help the development of my tooling for Notion (&lt;a href="https://kevinjalbert.com/introducing-notion-scripts/"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently made the decision to consolidate all my Notion related projects into a single repository. The goal is to increase cohesion to allow the tools to better interact with each other. It also puts everything in one place instead of spreading it out over multiple repositories. This approach does increase the size of the repository and the deployment/usage complexity for certain tools, but overall I feel that this decision will result in an easier way to use and develop with the Notion tools found there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Great Merge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great merge happened on December 27, 2019. On GitHub, &lt;code&gt;notion-heroku&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;notion-scripts&lt;/code&gt; were merged into &lt;code&gt;alfred-notion&lt;/code&gt;. I decided for &lt;code&gt;alfred-notion&lt;/code&gt; to be the main repository as it had the most &lt;em&gt;stars&lt;/em&gt; on GitHub and was the longest-tenured repository I have for Notion tools. I did rename the repository to &lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/notion-toolbox"&gt;&lt;code&gt;notion-toolbox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to better represent the mission and contents of this project. Fortunately, GitHub automatically handles the redirects from &lt;code&gt;alfred-notion&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;notion-toolbox&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to retain the commit history of each project by following the approach mentioned in this article on &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/altcampus/how-to-merge-two-or-multiple-git-repositories-into-one-9f8a5209913f"&gt;How to merge two or multiple git repositories into one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. This approach worked flawlessly for me, and was rather straightforward. The only thing I had to do was move each project&amp;rsquo;s contents into subdirectories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the merged repositories, I archived them following my approach listed in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://kevinjalbert.com/archive-unused-repositories/"&gt;Archive Unused Repositories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; that I blogged about last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue that I&amp;rsquo;ve hit right now is the &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt; (formerly &lt;code&gt;notion-heroku&lt;/code&gt;) &lt;a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/procfile#procfile-naming-and-location"&gt;expects certain files in the root directory to be deployable to Heroku&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve temporarily restructured the repository so that it works, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal as the tool itself is bleeding outside of its sub-directory. A better solution will be found in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The tools in &lt;code&gt;notion-toolbox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/"&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; tools that work in tandem together. All of these tools take advantage of a &lt;a href="https://kevinjalbert.com/my-weekly-notion-setup/"&gt;specific weekly/daily template&lt;/a&gt; that integrates with various tools and solutions present in this repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of the publish date of this post, the following tools are available. Each tool has a README file present in its corresponding sub-directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/notion-toolbox/tree/master/alfred"&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; workflow

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enables a handful of ways to interact with the template using shortcuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/notion-toolbox/tree/master/server"&gt;Server&lt;/a&gt; application

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enables an online (and backgrounded) interface to interact with the template&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Useful to connect with webhooks (e.g., &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com/maker_webhooks"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opens integrations with Google Assistant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to making more Notion tools in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Learn More About Yourself Using Personality Types</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/learn-more-about-yourself-using-personality-types/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/learn-more-about-yourself-using-personality-types/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2019-11-29T19:00:00-05:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">I want to present well-known tests that you can take to learn more about yourself from a personality perspective. For one hour of your time, you'll likely come away with a renewed and deeper understanding of who you are.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a firm believer that a comprehensive understanding of one&amp;rsquo;s true inner-self can only lead to better growth and relationships. We&amp;rsquo;re all uniquely different in our own ways, although there are sets of archetypes that we can closely associate with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Tests&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, the &lt;a href="https://www.myersbriggs.org/"&gt;Myers Briggs Type&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.enneagraminstitute.com/"&gt;Enneagram Type&lt;/a&gt; are the leaders in personality archetypes. The differences between these tests are out of the scope of this post. These are established institutions and you can pay for a complete test, although there are free alternatives, such as &lt;a href="https://www.16personalities.com/"&gt;16Personalities&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.9types.com/"&gt;9Types&lt;/a&gt; respectively. The results from these tests are often distilled down into a digestible format, however, large bodies of material do exist for each type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is likely that you already have a good idea of your underlying personality and some of the inner mechanisms that propel you forward. I would argue that you will still uncover something about yourself if you have not taken these two tests yet. There may be some deeper insights that will resonate with you. It is worth noting that the results shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be taken 100% as truth, but nonetheless it&amp;rsquo;s still worthwhile to know more about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Benefits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the results in hand, you can uncover and understand some of the inner-workings that make you tick. I personally found the information useful and insightful as it reaffirmed certain beliefs and values that I hold. I was pleased to see sections dedicated to relationships with other types, as well as personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An additional benefit is that you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to share your type with others (e.g., partner, boss, co-worker, friend), giving them a deeper understanding of &lt;em&gt;who you are&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Using iOS Shortcuts to Open Notion Pages</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kevinjalbert.com/using-ios-shortcuts-to-open-notion-pages/"/>
    <id>https://kevinjalbert.com/using-ios-shortcuts-to-open-notion-pages/</id>
    <updated>2020-08-30T22:52:46-04:00</updated>
    <published>2019-10-29T20:00:00-04:00</published>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Jalbert</name>
    </author>
    <description type="html">Learn how to quickly open Notion pages on your iOS device. See how I work around dynamic page links (e.g., current day/week) to open the correct pages from my Notion Weekly Template.</description>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently switched from Android back to iOS for my mobile device. I decided to take a look at &lt;a href="https://support.apple.com/en-ca/guide/shortcuts/welcome/ios"&gt;iOS Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt; as I never really got to play with them before. Given my recent obsession with &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/?r=6b8d609eb50943419db4d87c67fa558e"&gt;Notion [Referral]&lt;/a&gt; I decided to see how I can put iOS Shortcuts to use here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through two examples of using iOS Shortcuts to open Notion Pages. The first one uses a normal Notion page, and the second one uses the &lt;em&gt;current&lt;/em&gt; day/week pages from my &lt;a href="/my-weekly-notion-setup/"&gt;highly-tailored weekly template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Open Notion Page from iOS Home Screen&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you can do is create a shortcut on your home screen that opens to a specific page in Notion. For example, you could have a page holding your todos, shopping list, latest project, etc. In my opinion, this is really useful if you frequently use specific pages in Notion on your mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Notion Page Link&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to get the &lt;em&gt;Page Link&lt;/em&gt; from Notion. On iOS, you get this link by clicking the &lt;code&gt;...&lt;/code&gt; on a page in Notion and then &lt;em&gt;Copy Link&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: You can find the current Page Link in the Web interface for Notion as well, although the user interface will be slightly different.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="display: flex"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/2019-10-30-using-ios-shortcuts-to-open-notion-pages/notion-page-step1.jpg" style="width: 49%"/&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/2019-10-30-using-ios-shortcuts-to-open-notion-pages/notion-page-step2.jpg" style="width: 49%"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your clipboard, you will have a link that looks like the following: &lt;code&gt;https://www.notion.so/Example-page-721c581be9734ad09480d0cc16f774fd&lt;/code&gt;. If visit this link, your browser will open the Notion web application to that page. Unfortunately, this will open the page in the web application in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to open the native Notion application. We can accomplish that using a custom URL Schema that Notion provides for iOS/macOS. &lt;strong&gt;Replacing &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;notion&lt;/code&gt; in our link (e.g., &lt;code&gt;notion://www.notion.so/Example-page-721c581be9734ad09480d0cc16f774fd&lt;/code&gt;) will now open the Notion page in the native Notion application (if opened with Safari).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Shortcut to Open Notion Page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we can start by creating our iOS Shortcut to open the Notion page. As shown in the images below, our shortcut is just one step to open the &lt;code&gt;notion://&lt;/code&gt; page link with Safari. Finally, we can add this to the home screen, and now we have a single press shortcut that opens directly to the page we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="display: flex"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/2019-10-30-using-ios-shortcuts-to-open-notion-pages/notion-page-step3.jpg" style="width: 49%"/&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/2019-10-30-using-ios-shortcuts-to-open-notion-pages/notion-page-step4.jpg" style="width: 49%"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Open my Current Day/Week Page&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/575fc46b4e1b486dab30c4ef42cdf180"&gt;Click to get iOS Shortcut to Open Current Day Notion Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As previously noted, I have a more elaborate Notion setup (more details about &lt;a href="/my-weekly-notion-setup/"&gt;highly-tailored weekly template&lt;/a&gt;) where I have unique Notion pages for each day and week. My goal is to have a &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;Notion Day&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&amp;#39;Notion Week&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; shortcut on my home screen for quick access. Unfortunately, the page link for the current day and week change daily/weekly, and thus the previous solution doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fetching the Dynamic URLs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently have a web application running that exposes an API (&lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/notion-heroku"&gt;&lt;code&gt;notion-heroku&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), allowing me to interact with my Notion account through HTTP requests. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently &lt;a href="https://github.com/kevinjalbert/notion-heroku/pull/3"&gt;added a feature&lt;/a&gt; that exposes the &lt;code&gt;notion://&lt;/code&gt; page URLs for the current day/week when I make a request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;code&gt; curl https://notion-heroku.herokuapp.com/current_links.json &lt;span class="nt"&gt;-H&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"api_token: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$API_TOKEN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;"&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nt"&gt;-s&lt;/span&gt; | jq
&lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"current_day"&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"notion://www.notion.so/YHuWdvUQ8nc5gBgkqHexDToWRzGvuP6e"&lt;/span&gt;,
  &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"current_week"&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"notion://www.notion.so/kG7jQamppo4RRGc7voAC7elyGDeg7a70"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shortcut isn&amp;rsquo;t too hard to create afterwards and ends up as a three-step shortcut:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the HTTP network call.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access the value from the JSON response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open value (Notion page URL) in Safari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div style="display: flex"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/2019-10-30-using-ios-shortcuts-to-open-notion-pages/notion-current-day.jpg" style="width: 49%"/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shortcut works well, but it has two drawbacks. It &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; has to make the network call to get the page links, it can be slow based on latency and it requires network access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Performance and Robustness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address the drawbacks of the previous shortcut demonstration in the last section, we can cache the response from the &lt;code&gt;notion-heroku&lt;/code&gt; server. Caching the results for a day then makes it so only the first usage of the shortcut requires a network call and all subsequent usage uses a cached file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/575fc46b4e1b486dab30c4ef42cdf180"&gt;new and improved iOS Shortcut&lt;/a&gt; now contains over 25 steps, although it handles caching, cache invalidation, and a notification if the server didn&amp;rsquo;t respond. Using the shortcut when there is a cached value feels faster to me and it even works while in airplane mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following video gives a walkthrough of the shortcuts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class="youtube-embed" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oGYWF5EpwbQ" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;The Possibilities with iOS Shortcuts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, iOS Shortcuts open up a lot of interesting possibilities. The fact that you are able to make and use API calls is very powerful on its own. I can see myself connecting more stuff to &lt;a href="https://ifttt.com"&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;. With respect to Notion, I&amp;rsquo;ll likely continue to expand on my &lt;code&gt;notion-heroku&lt;/code&gt; server and see what I can do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
